{
    "questions": [
        
        {
            "question": "151.India EXIM Finserv IFSC Private Ltd is to be set up in which place?",
            "options": [
                "Mumbai",
                "Ahmedabad",
                "New Delhi",
                "Chennai"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ahmedabad"
        },
        {
            "question": "152.Rhythm Sangwan, who was seen in the news, plays which sports?",
            "options": [
                "Wrestling",
                "Cricket",
                "Shooting",
                "Hockey"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Shooting"
        },
        {
            "question": "153.Which airport has been recognised as the world\u2019s most punctual airport, as per the recentreport released by Cirium?",
            "options": [
                "Chennai Airport",
                "Hyderabad Airport",
                "Mumbai Airport",
                "New Delhi Airport"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Hyderabad Airport"
        },
        {
            "question": "154.Which country is set to launch \u2018NVS-01 Navigation Satellite\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "India",
                "UAE",
                "Russia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "India"
        },
        {
            "question": "155.Where is the \u2018Great Grandfather Tree\u2019 located?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "China",
                "Greece",
                "Chile"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Chile"
        },
        {
            "question": "156.Sanchar Saathi portal, which was launched recently, is used for which activity?",
            "options": [
                "Grievance Redressal",
                "Tracking Lost or Stolen Mobile",
                "Nomination for Awards",
                "GST Filing"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Tracking Lost or Stolen Mobile"
        },
        {
            "question": "157.Which institution developed the \u2018non-aqueous all-organic redox flow battery\u2019 (NORFB)?",
            "options": [
                "IISc Bengaluru",
                "IIT Madras",
                "IIT Delhi",
                "IIT Kanpur"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IIT Madras"
        },
        {
            "question": "158.Which department launched the \u2018Automated Return Scrutiny Module for GST returns\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "CBIC",
                "NASSCOM",
                "NITI Aayog",
                "RBI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "CBIC"
        },
        {
            "question": "159.Which Union Ministry announced the finalization of the Model Prisons Act, 2023?",
            "options": [
                "Ministry of Home Affairs",
                "Ministry of Defence",
                "Ministry of Housing and Urban Affairs",
                "Ministry of External Affairs"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ministry of Home Affairs"
        },
        {
            "question": "160.Which institution released the \u2018World Tourism Barometer\u2019 Report?",
            "options": [
                "UNICEF",
                "UNWTO",
                "UNDP",
                "World Bank"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "UNWTO"
        },
        {
            "question": "162.Amy Pope, the first woman Director General of the International Organization for Migration, isfrom which country?",
            "options": [
                "United States",
                "Germany",
                "Australia",
                "UK"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "United States"
        },
        {
            "question": "163.Which institution released the \u2018Spring 2023 Economic Forecast\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "World Bank",
                "European Commission",
                "WEF",
                "IMF"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "European Commission"
        },
        {
            "question": "164.Pita Limjaroenrat, who was seen in the news, is a political leader from which country?",
            "options": [
                "Ukraine",
                "Russia",
                "Thailand",
                "Myanmar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Thailand"
        },
        {
            "question": "165.\u2018Initiative on Critical and Emerging Technology (iCET)\u2019 is an initiative between India and whichcountry?",
            "options": [
                "Australia",
                "USA",
                "France",
                "UAE"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "166. ‘Archopterus anjiensis’, the oldest sea scorpion, has been found in which country?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "China",
                "Argentina",
                "South Africa"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "China"
        },
        {
            "question": "167.Which documentary won the \u201cBest Long Documentary Award\u201d at the South Asian Film Festivalof Montreal 2023?",
            "options": [
                "Gujarat",
                "Gauri",
                "Scam",
                "Bharat Mata Ki"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Gauri"
        },
        {
            "question": "168.\u2018Himcare scheme\u2019, which was seen in the news, belongs to which category?",
            "options": [
                "Medical Insurance scheme",
                "Education Guidance scheme",
                "Financial Aid Scheme",
                "Farmers Aid Scheme"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Medical Insurance scheme"
        },
        {
            "question": "169.Which milestone has been achieved by the \u2018Innovations for Defence Excellence (iDEX)?",
            "options": [
                "100",
                "250",
                "500",
                "1000"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "250"
        },
        {
            "question": "170.Which is the first state in the country to introduce a welfare fund for MGNREGS workers?",
            "options": [
                "Tamil Nadu",
                "Kerala",
                "Telangana",
                "Odisha"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Kerala"
        },
        {
            "question": "171.Which state hosted the joint flood relief exercise \u2018Jal Rahat\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Assam",
                "Punjab",
                "Goa",
                "Vishakhapatnam"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Assam"
        },
        {
            "question": "172.Which institution released the \u2018Turning off the Tap: How the world can end plastic pollution andcreate a circular economy\u2019 Report?",
            "options": [
                "UNICEF",
                "UNEP",
                "UNFCCC",
                "UNDP"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "UNEP"
        },
        {
            "question": "173.Which city is the host of LOGISEM \u2013 23 \u2013 the National Logistics Management Seminar?",
            "options": [
                "New Delhi",
                "Mumbai",
                "Panjim",
                "Guwahati"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "174.Tungnath Temple, which was seen in the news, is located in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Uttarakhand",
                "Jammu and Kashmir",
                "Assam",
                "Rajasthan"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Uttarakhand"
        },
        {
            "question": "176.Auschwitz museum, which was seen in the news, is located in which country?",
            "options": [
                "Poland",
                "France",
                "Italy",
                "Finland"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Poland"
        },
        {
            "question": "177.Which institution is associated with \u2018Surety Bonds\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "RBI",
                "IRDAI",
                "SEBI",
                "NPCI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IRDAI"
        },
        {
            "question": "178.Sea butterflies belong to a sub order of which species?",
            "options": [
                "Butterfly",
                "Snail",
                "Fish",
                "Turtle"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Snail"
        },
        {
            "question": "179.Which city is the National Ayush Mission Conclave?",
            "options": [
                "New Delhi",
                "Mumbai",
                "Mysuru",
                "Varanasi"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "181.When is the \u2018World Telecom Day\u2019 observed every year?",
            "options": [
                "May 12",
                "May 15",
                "May 17",
                "May 20"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "May 17"
        },
        {
            "question": "182.\u2018Robert E Lucas\u2019 who passed away recently, was associated with which field?",
            "options": [
                "Physics",
                "Economics",
                "Medicine",
                "Literature"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Economics"
        },
        {
            "question": "183.Linda Yaccarino has been named as the CEO of which Multi-national Exchange?",
            "options": [
                "Twitter",
                "Microsoft",
                "Google",
                "Apple"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Twitter"
        },
        {
            "question": "184.Which institution organises the \u2018Operation Dhvast\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Coast Guard",
                "National Investigation Agency",
                "Indian Navy",
                "Reserve Bank of India"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "National Investigation Agency"
        },
        {
            "question": "185.What is the budget outlay of the \u2018Production Linked Incentive Scheme 2.0 for IT Hardware\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Rs 12000 crore",
                "Rs 17000 crore",
                "Rs 32000 crore",
                "Rs 37000 crore"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Rs 17000 crore"
        },
        {
            "question": "186.Rice, maize, and cotton crops are usually sown in which season?",
            "options": [
                "Kharif",
                "Rabi",
                "Zaid",
                "Monsoon"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Kharif"
        },
        {
            "question": "187.Platytholus clemensi is a newly discovered genus and species of pachycephalosaurid dinosaurfound in which country?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "China",
                "USA",
                "Australia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "188.Death cap mushroom is a poisonous fungus found across which region?",
            "options": [
                "South Asia",
                "Europe",
                "Oceania",
                "North America"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Europe"
        },
        {
            "question": "189.Which Union Ministry launched the '75\/25' initiative?",
            "options": [
                "Ministry of Health and Family Welfare",
                "Ministry of MSME",
                "Ministry of Power",
                "Ministry of External Affairs"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ministry of Health and Family Welfare"
        },
        {
            "question": "190.Which state\/UT launched the \u2018Matsyakara Bharosa scheme\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Andhra Pradesh",
                "Kerala",
                "Rajasthan",
                "Punjab"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Andhra Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "191.Which Indian budget airline has collapsed and cancelled all flights?",
            "options": [
                "SpiceJet",
                "Go First",
                "Jet Konnect",
                "Air Asia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Go First"
        },
        {
            "question": "192.Which state launched the State Dashboard and a data and analytics-powered platform tomonitor government schemes?",
            "options": [
                "Odisha",
                "West Bengal",
                "Assam",
                "Gujarat"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Odisha"
        },
        {
            "question": "193.Which country is set to manufacture generic variant of long-acting cabotegravir (CAB-LA) drug,used for HIV prevention?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "USA",
                "South Africa",
                "Israel"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "South Africa"
        },
        {
            "question": "195.Which country launched the \u2018Spitzer Space Telescope\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Russia",
                "USA",
                "UAE"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "196.Which institution proposed a \u2018Framework for Unexplained Suspicious Trading Pattern\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "RBI",
                "SEBI",
                "NPCI",
                "IRDAI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "SEBI"
        },
        {
            "question": "197.Which institution proposed changes to the definition of \u2018Unpublished Price SensitiveInformation (UPSI)\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "RBI",
                "SEBI",
                "NPCI",
                "NITI Aayog"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "SEBI"
        },
        {
            "question": "198.Which city is the host of the \u2018Wings India 2024\u2019 event?",
            "options": [
                "Hyderabad",
                "Bengaluru",
                "Chennai",
                "Gandhi Nagar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Hyderabad"
        },
        {
            "question": "199.Which institution developed the \u2018Zorawar Light Tank\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "ISRO",
                "DRDO",
                "BEL",
                "BHEL"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "DRDO"
        },
        {
            "question": "200.Vladivostok Port, which was seen in the news, is located in which country?",
            "options": [
                "Ukraine",
                "Russia",
                "Japan",
                "Brazil"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Russia"
        }
    ]
}